Futon, clothes, shoes, toothbrush.
What else do you need-
What?
Rin, don't go off on your own like that.
You really scared me.
Yes~
Daikichi, get me the green one.
Come on, let's go.
It's dangerous if you don't hold on to my hand.
I'll be in danger?
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことは　分かんない
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau nanika ga chigau
これって　犠牲とは違う　何かが違う
This is different from sacrificing, very different.
batsugeemu jaa nante omou wa nai
罰ゲームじゃあ　なんて思うわない
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
tte nande nanoka ha wakannai
って　なんでなのかは　分かんない
I can't really say well what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと　釈然としないけど
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nantemonjanai
キミの存在　今大事だ　なんてもんじゃない
but "important" cannot be used to describe your existence any more.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai
終わらないことなんて　この世のどこにもない
There's nothing that will last forever without coming to an end.
naku no ha tsurai janai no
泣くのは辛いじゃないの
Crying is a very painful thing
I know! Sweet drops! Sweet drops!
zutto yume mite itaine
ずっと　夢見ていたいね
I have always wanted to dream
motto yasashiku shitaine
もっと　優しくしたいね
To be able to be more gentle
kimi to iraretara happy!
キミと居られたら　happy!
Just being together with you is happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って　強いね
Girls are strong,
dakedo tokitoki yowai ne
だけど　ときとき　弱いね
but at times, they are weak.
bokura no negai ha happy! happy! happy...
僕らの願いは　happy! happy! happy...
Our wish is to be happy! Happy! Happy!
sonna hibi mo happy!
そんな日々も happy!
Such happy days!
Just wanna make you happy...
Are there always this many parents shopping with their children?
That looks nice.
This?
Yeah.
Let's see.
Yep, it's not too bad.
What size do you wear?
I don't know.
Turn around, Rin.
Like this?
Where exactly do I measure?
I don't know~!
Stop flapping!
What other clothes do you need?
Pyjamas, underwear, shirts, socks.
Aren't you buying any skirts?
All you have are pants.
Skirts aren't allowed in daycare.
I see.
Daycare?
I forgot... tomorrow is Monday.
Daikichi, I'm tired.
We're almost there, so hang in there.
Okay~
I'm hungry.
Sign: Apple Futon Shop
We're almost home.
Okay~
Skipping classes again?
You're slacking again, you lazybones.
Always bringing back useless stuff...
I will get angry, you know!
What did you say, bastard!
Don't touch me!
Let go of me!
Sorry about that.
Hello, this is the Maeda family.
It was so sudden; my condolences for your loss.
Yes, please wait.
Haruko-san, it's Daikichi-san.
Coming, sorry!
Haruko, excuse me; I didn't know your cellphone number.
It's fine.
Say, what do you need to enrol in a daycare?
Daycare?
What? You really brought Rin-chan home?
Wait, are you sure it's okay?
I'm fine at the moment.
At the moment?
Also, I can't afford to take any more leave from work tomorrow.
What's the procedure?
About that, you don't get in that quick.
Can't you do anything about it?
Even if you ask that...
In any case, you should ask at the city offices.
It's a Sunday night.
What?
No, just something happening.
Mama, is that Rin-chan? Is that Rin-chan?
Are you all right?
Hey Reina! I'm discussing something important here.
Rin-chan!
There is a temporary emergency daycare.
Temporary emergency daycare?
Rin-chan!
What's wrong?
Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Dai-chan?
It's nothing, something minor over here.
I'll be done shortly, so wait first!
Reina can't wait any longer.
Haruko-san, I'm turning off the burner for your miso soup.
Okay, sorry about that.
Hey, you sound really busy. Later I'll-
RIN-CHAN!
Osu City Council
temporary emergency da
temporary emergency day
temporary emergency dayca
temporary emergency daycar
temporary emergency daycare
Wow, there's not many.
The time I need to get to work is doubled, all of a sudden.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
This one may be nearby, but it's impossible for me to get off work by six.
Let's play again next time.
Okay, bye bye Reina-chan. See you.
This one doesn't look too bad.
Temporary Emergency Daycare can only be up to 10 days, at most.
Bath.
Wait just a bit longer.
Daikichi, Daikichi, it's morning~!
Okay, sorry.
You were sleeping over here?
The futon is strangely warm, you know.
Take it off!
Yeah, right away.
You'll be going to the daycare today.
Itadakimasu!
You shouldn't put your elbows on the table while eating.
Okay, I apologise.
Listen carefully, the daycare we're heading to now is only temporary.
Temporary?
Means you'll be going to this one before an official one has been decided.
What does "official" mean?
It means the proper one.
No, actually that's incorrect.
My hair is fine!
Are you okay?
A-All right.
N-No problem.
I see it.
Let me down, let me down!
What? What?
You get embarrassed when the other kids see it?
Daikichi.
Yeah.
I'm leaving her in your care.
Okay, have a safe trip.
Don't make that kind of face.
I won't be able to get you until dark, but I'll rush here as soon as I can.
It's a promise.
Pinky promise, if you tell a lie, you will swallow a thousand needles...
...God damn it! It's a promise!
The words are wrong.
I'll be going. Wait for me, Rin.
My bad, Rin.
I wasn't able to be considerate of your feelings.
Whether it's about your mother, or Grandpa's death.
None of these things are easy to take.
The lonely reality of being left all by yourself.
You must also be thinking I'll abandon you, too.
I'm really sorry.
I won't do something like this a second time.
Read this?
Okay.
Kawachi-san, let's eat.
I'm eating this.
I'm rushing so that I can leave early.
Oh, I see.
I'll be going then.
Trying so hard even at the start of the month.
You're wrong.
Please take a picture of this sample.
Okay.
Kawachi-san!
Someone is asking for you on outside line #4 about the internal exhibition.
Coming.
Thanks for waiting, Kawachi speaking.
Bye bye!
Let's continue.
Okay.
Kawachi~
Yeah, excuse me.
You're late!
Sorry.
Get your jacket.
Yes!
Rin-chan, don't ruin it.
Okay.
Bye bye.
Bye bye...
Yes, a moment please.
Kawachi-san.
It's Miyata-san from Mitsumoto Trading.
Transfer it over.
It's Kawachi, sorry for the wait.
Yes, this is Kawachi.
Yes, I'm really sorry.
Yes, I'll be leaving the office in a short while. Sorry about that.
It's so far!
The daycare!
Rin, sorry I'm late.
Welcome back.
I'm terribly sorry.
Rin.
Oh, french fries? They look delicious!
Kinpira!
Note: Kinpira is a method of cooking by simmering root vegetables.
Text: Daikichi
Swallow...
...a thousand needles.
I'm leaving all these to you.
Kawachi-san, you've to sign.
Worrying about it is needless, but what happens if I really find a girlfriend?
Daikichi! Daikichi!
Wake up!
Yeah, sorry.
Kawachi, this should have been sent yesterday.
I'm extremely sorry.
Coming from you, that's rare.
Sorry.
I've already apologised to them.
Sorry about that, I'll contact them later.
It's been a while; let's have a drink.
Sorry, but I can't make it today.
What about tomorrow?
I have some things tomorrow, too...
What's that?
Isn't that great?
What?
Get on.
I'm fine.
Daikichi?
Hold on tight!
Charge!
Daikichi, don't let the moon catch us!
All right~!
Never ending.
How long can I sustain this kind of lifestyle?
Osu City
Mother and Child Health Handbook
All these belong to Rin-chan.
Even though there's only so few of them, the MCH Handbook and other important documents are inside.
Raising a child is very difficult, even if it's on a short term.
All this is hardest on Rin.
Sorry about it; I'm taking a look.
The mouth hasn't changed a bit.
Our relatives are describing you like some sort of a devil.
Though really, who's the real devil here, Masako-san?
nichiyou no hare ta hiru sagari
日曜の晴れた昼さがり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通い慣れたいつもの道が眩しく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らす暖かい太陽と　隣に君がいれば
The warm sun shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Feeling merry
utae Life Life Life
歌え　Life　Life　Life
Sing life, life, life
koe ha dokomade mo
声はどこまでも
I can hear our voices anywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Riding on the soaring wind
utae Life Life Life
歌え　Life　Life　Life
Sing life, life, life
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
What's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
Anyway, which side are you sleeping?
I-Is that m-mine!?
That's sweat!
Yes, right, sweat it is.
I'm going to remove the sheets, give me a hand.
I told you that's sweat!
That's also what I said!